# William Bille Meyling

Github: https://github.com/willthbill; LinkedIn: https://bit.ly/linkedin-wbm

A friendly 22 year old Computer Science student with a passion for Algorithm Engineering – especially within Computational Geometry and Graph Algorithms. I have spend the past 8 years finding and pursuing my interests, winning numerous national and international competitions along the way. I see myself as an innovative person, who appreciates simple solutions to complicated problems. My attention to detail, systematic mindset and curiosity makes me good at planning and quickly building large projects, making few mistakes along the way. My native language is Danish.



E-mail: williambillemeyling@gmail.com

#### EDUCATION

University of Copenhagen

Bachelor in Computer Science. Grade: 12

Courses in Algorithms and Cybersecurity

DDD training camps and DDC Cybersecurity courses

NEXT Sukkertoppen Gymnasium

High school. Computer Science and Math. GPA: 11.8

Copenhagen, Denmark Sep. 2020 – Aug. 2023

Denmark

Sep. 2018 – May. 2022 Copenhagen, Denmark

Aug. 2016 - Jun. 2020

#### EXPERIENCE

University of Copenhagen

Teaching assistant in the course 'Algorithms and Data structures'

Jobindex

Full-stack Developer. Tools: MySQL, Perl, Vue.js

Copenhagen, Denmark

Feb. 2023 - Mar. 2023

Copenhagen, Denmark

Feb. 2021 - Jan. 2022

Oct. 2020 - present

Dansk Datalogi Dyst (Danish National Olympiad in Informatics)

Volunteer. Designing algorithmic problems used to select students for the national team. Train-

ing the national team for the International Olympiad in Informatics (IOI). Preparing courses in advanced (beyond bachelor-level) algorithmic techniques. Deputy leader at IOI 2022. Vice chairman of the technical committee of BOI 2023 (International Competition) (with salary).

Arnvind Group

Frontend Developer. Tools: React. Responsible for a large complicated wep-app.

). G. 1. D. 1.

Denmark, Indonesia, Germany

Copenhagen, Denmark

Apr. 2019 - Mar. 2020

### AWARDS AND ACHIEVEMENTS

#### Winner of Computational Geometry Challenge 2023

"Unofficial World Championships in Geometric Algorithms" – a research competition called CG:SHOP. Qualified me for SoCG (the most prestigious Computational geometry conference). Media coverage in DR:P1, Ekstra-Bladet, videnskab.dk and more. Statement at https://bit.ly/scienceku-wbm23

Online and in Dallas, Texas

Sep. 2022 - Jun. 2023

#### Winner of Unge Forskere 2020

Danish National Youth Research Championships 2020. Project about Efficient Graph-based Image-segmentation. Media coverage in DR:P1, DR:P3, Jyllands-posten, videnskab.dk and more. Statement at https://bit.ly/ungefor-wbm20

Copenhagen, Denmark (remote) ased Apr. 2020

## 'Best Computational Project' at European Science Championships

Unge Forskere project received the PRACE Award at EUCYS 2020. Statement at https://bit.ly/prace-wbm21

Salamanca, Spain (remote)

Sep. 2021

### Top 52% at the International Olympiad in Informatics (IOI) 2020

Competitive Programming. IOI participant in 2019 and 2020. Also participated in Baltic Olympiad in Informatics in 2019 and 2020.

Singapore (remote) Apr. 2019 - Sep. 2020

## 2nd place at Danish AI Championships 2022

AI Engineering Competition

Copenhagen, Denmark

Denmark, Netherlands and Online

# $2\mathrm{nd}$ place at Danish Programming Championships 2021

Competitive Programming. 4th in 2020, 2nd in 2021, 3rd in 2022. Qualified for NWERC all three years (Northwestern Europe Regional Contest). Will participate in 2023.

 $Nov.\ 2020-present$ 

Oct. 2022

Denmark

### Winner of Danish National Olympiad in Informatics 2019 and 2020

Dansk Datalogi Dyst. Competitive Programming. Part of the National Team.

Apr. 2019 - Sep. 2020

Master Title on CodeForces

Online

Competitive Programming. Top 1600 in the world. https://bit.ly/cf-wbm

Sep. 2021 - present

### Next Generation Award 2020 (Skau Reipurth)

Given "as an acknowledgement of his talent, hard work and passion for programming". https://bit.ly/skau-wbm20

 $Copenhagen,\,Denmark$ 

Nov. 2020

## Finalist in the Danish Cyber Championships 2022

De Danske Cybermesterskaber 2022. Cybersecurity (CTF) Competition.

Copenhagen, Denmark

May. 2022

### PROJECTS & PUBLICATIONS

- ExtensionCC: An efficient Convex Cover algorithm developed for CG:SHOP 2023. Publication: https://bit.ly/SoCGpub-wbm23. Bachelor-thesis: https://bit.ly/ba-wbm
- Universal Autonomous Graph-based Image Segmentation with Near-linear Average Complexity: Unge Forskere project. See more at https://bit.ly/eucys-wbm
- Pacup: Open-source tool unifying Linux package managers and making systems reproducible: https://bit.ly/pacup-wbm
- Opener.nvim: Open-source Neovim plugin for workspace / context switching: https://bit.ly/opener-nvim
- Codify: Chrome extension with over 10000 installations.

### SKILLS & INTERESTS

- Theoretical Computer Science: Graph algorithms, Computational Geometry, Software Design, AI
- Favorite Programming Languages: C++, Python, JavaScript, C, Rust
- Other: Linux, DevOps, Web development, Cybersecurity, Automation, Latex, Video editing

#### References

• Mikkel Vind Abrahamsen (Bachelor supervisor)

E-mail: miab@di.ku.dk Mobile: +45 20787534